

M.Sc. Computer Engineer • T-Shaped Software Engineer specialized in .NET with some React, Angular, TypeScript experience with a DevOps mindset

□ request with a message | ■ hi@alpcoker.com | # alpcoker.com | □ alpcoker | □ alpcoker

Bio - Background

I'm a software and technology enthusiast who loves to be in the center of creating software that is providing value for humanity or makes companies make great profits or makes them efficient. I identify myself as a problem solver who is not a specific tech fanatic. I apply the most optimum solution when and where necessary. I have the most experience as a full-stack engineer who is specialized in backend and infrastructure.

I have twelve years of experience and have worked for six companies from start-ups to big enterprise companies. I have worked in the following industries; cryptocurrency, travel, defense, mission-critical, government, and geographic information systems.

Besides my professional career, I have two open-source projects that I love to be working on. As an achievement, I have also one first place and two degrees in two competitions for professionals.

Career Objectives

I love to work with the best of my skills for getting our(my) project to reach its goals. I will be satisfied if my output is used by other people and it is completing our goals one by one. I always try to put my best effort to reach desired quality for any kind of work in our remaining time.

I always try/want to be (stay as) an innovative and target-driven engineer. I seek better solutions, and best practices not just in my career, but also apply them to my life. I look for new challenges, goals, and responsibilities that can keep me active and fresh in my life. While I am working with my colleagues, I always try to move/develop/focus together. Because there can't be only a single human behind any big successes.

Experience _____

BtcTurk - Cryptocurrency Exchange & Platform - Highest Cryptocurrency Volume in Turkey

Remote, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2022 - Jun. 2022

- I worked on the cash flow team. I was responsible for fiat deposits and withdrawals on a cryptocurrency exchange which has a very high market value. The platform was using a microservices architecture. I was developing and monitored the system health.
- I maintained existing money transfer integrations and was developing a SaaS solution for companies to manage their money transfers.
- Used technologies: .NET 6, RabbitMQ, Microsoft SQL Server, Azure, Elastic Stack, Redis, Atlassian Products

Otelz - Online Travel Agency - Most Popular in Turkey

Remote, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar. 2021 - Feb. 2022

- I developed Expedia integration to enable the company to expand abroad. With this partnership, the company can list hotels not just in Turkey but also in the world. This integration includes data synchronization between two companies' different models, searching, listing hotel availability, and making payments and reservations.
- I developed a new channel manager (a system for hotels to manage their availability in real-time) integration that is widely used by big resorts. For our existing channel manager integrations with a count of 25, I maintained and monitored them.
- Used technologies: .NET 5, React, Microsoft SQL Server, Azure DevOps, Elastic Stack, AWS, Redis, Atlassian Products

T2 🗗 - Defence Industry Ankara, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Aug. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- · I redesigned the architecture of their mission critical desktop systems to their intranet web environment.
- I analyzed their existing complex processes and applied new solutions which is more simple and scalable.
- Used technologies: React, Java 11, Spring, Kotlin, TimescaleDB with PostgreSQL, Elastic Stack, GitLab Enterprise

Havelsan 🗹 - Defence Industry - Reference: Hülya Vural - Software Engineering Manager 🗹

Ankara, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & ARCHITECT

May 2017 - Aug. 2020

- I was designing architecture, defining development standards, fixing performance issues, new system integration, technology stack changes, deployment problems, security flaws, new framework features.
- Used technologies: ASP.NET Core 3.1, ASP.NET MVC, Angular, Oracle Database, Elastic Stack, Redis, Team Foundation Server

BilgeAdam 🗹 - Outsourcing for Government Offices - Reference: Seçkin Bedük - Software Development Director 🗷

Ankara, Turkey

SOFTWARE CONSULTANT

Aug. 2014 - May 2017

- I replaced a high traffic government public service with a new modern architecture to solve previous maintenance difficulties, lack of analyzing big data, lack of other system integration and slowness problems.
- Used technologies: Windows Presentation Foundation, ASP.NET Core, SQL Server, SQL Server Integration Services, Team Foundation Server

Başarsoft ☑ - Geographic Information System Company - Reference: Emrah Yılmaz - R&D Manager ☑

Ankara, Turkey

R&D SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2010 - Jan. 2014

- I developed Windows CE, Windows Mobile, tablet applications which are connected systems (client-server) and navigation systems customized by customer needs. The most notable project that I developed was a navigation system for blind people.
- <u>Used technologies:</u> .NET Compact Framework, ASP.NET Web Services, SQL Server, Oracle, TCP/IP, ASP.NET, Team Foundation Server.

JUNE 28, 2022 ALP ÇOKER · RÉSUMÉ

OSS - Open Source Software

photo-cli, Extract when and where (reverse geocoding) your photos are taken, copy into a new organized .NET folder with various folder & file naming strategies, export into CSV files.

photo-cli 🖸

.NET

PackBlock, .NET & React toolchain for developers to rapidly develop customizable and extensible web applications. Private repo, need invitation.

PackBlock 🖸

Skills (w/years of experience)

C# (12), JavaScript(7), Typescript(3), Python(2), Golang(1), Kotlin(1), Java(1), R(1) Languages

.NET(12), ASP.NET(9), React(3), Angular(1), Vue.js(1), HTTP-REST API(8), OAuth-OIDC(2), WPF(4), Windows Forms(3), Spring Boot(1), **Technologies**

Hadoop(1), Spark(1), HTML(8), CSS(5)

Microservices(4), Message Broker(3), Hexagonal(2), Miniservices(2), CQS & CQRS(2), Monolithic(9), Layered & n-tier(7), MVC(3), **Architecture**

Service-Oriented Architecture(4), Modular(4), Client-Server(2), Outbox(1), TDD(1), Strangler(1), API Composition(1)

SDLC Rapid application development(4), Kanban(3), Scrum(2), Extreme Programming(2), Spiral Model(1)

Database MS-SQL Server(10), PostgreSQL(7), Elastic Search(6), Redis(6), Oracle(4), MongoDB(3), Prometheus(2), HBase(1) **Platforms** Kibana(6), RabbitMQ(2), Kafka(2), Grafana(2), Kubernetes(1), Fluentd(1), Camunda Workflow(1), Jaeger(1)

Azure DevOps-TFS(8), Docker(6), Linux(7), Git(5), GitHub(3), AWS(2), Azure(1), Heroku(1), GitLab(2), Atlassian(1), NGINX(2), NPM(1), **DevOps**

Rider(6), WebStorm(4), PyCharm(3), DataGrip(4), VS Code(4), Linux(10), Windows(19), macOS(2), Visual Studio(10), Postman(5) Tools

Achievements

2021 Third place with our team, Havelsan Hackathon 2020

2010 Finalist with our team, Microsoft Imagine Cup 2010

Ankara, Turkey Istanbul, Turkey

Competition Winner Istanbul, Turkey

MICROSOFT & TURKCELL May. 2009

 I have participated and won first place in a Mobile Application Development Competition which was hosted by Microsoft Turkey and Turkcell (the biggest mobile operator company in Turkey). My application is a social network for Windows Mobile users. With this application users create places and fill it's profile to be search by others. They can also share and tweet their locations within the application. This application very similar to Foursquare/Swarm but I have developed them they have published.

Education

2010-2013 Master of Science in Computer Engineering, Çankaya University (GPA 3,6 over 4) Ankara, Turkey 2006-2010 Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering, Çankaya University (GPA 3,2 over 4) Ankara, Turkey

Certifications

2018	M001: MongoDB Basics 🕘, M101P: MongoDB for Developers 🕘, M201: MongoDB Performance 🕘 ,	MongoDB University	
	MongoDB University	Mongoob oniversity	
2016	The Data Scientist's Toolbox, 🖒 , R Programming 🖒 , Getting and Cleaning Data 🖒 ,	Coursera	
	Exploratory Data Analysis 🕘 , Reproducible Research 😩 , Johns Hopkins University		
	Graph Analytics for Big Data 🕘 , Hadoop Platform and Application Framework 🕘 ,		
2016	Introduction to Big Data Analytics 🕘 , Introduction to Big Data 🕘 , Machine Learning With Big Data	Coursera	
	们, University of California, San Diego		
2016	Machine Learning: Regression 🕘 , Machine Learning: Classification 🕘 ,	Coursera	
	Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach 😩, University of Washington		
2016	Advanced Techniques for Designing HTML5 Apps 🕘, HTML5 Coding Essentials and Best Practices 🕘,	, edX	
	World Wide Web Consortium (W3C)		
2015	Data Structures and Algorithms 🕘 , Algorithmic Toolbox 🕘 , University of California, San Diego	Coursera	
2015	Introduction to R (2), DataCamp	DataCamp	
2015	Computational Thinking and Data Science 🕘 , Computer Science and Programming Using Python 🕘	edX	
	Massachusetts Institute of Technology		